Finding Aid for the Brian Urquhart Collection of Material about Ralph Bunche, ca. 1932-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Kashmir,; Ralph J. Bunche Trip - UN Missions., 1964-1967 April 7-21, 1964.; [Boxes 18-19, 4 folders]
  - Confidential memo: Secretary General-Nesterenko. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Letters: V.J. Betts-R.J. Bunche. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., April 9-16, 1966. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Gauthier, Tassara, re United Nations Military Observer Group in India and Pakistan. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., September 26, 1967. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Excerpts from UN Yearbook., 1968. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Cyprus,; Ralph J. Bunche's Middle East Trip,; Ndola, Kenya., 1964 April 1964.; [Box 19, 6 folders]
  - List of R.J. Bunche photos., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Archive group list: UN Peacekeeping Force in Cyprus. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - List of Secretary General's reports to Security Council., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - UN Yearbook., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., June 13-20, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Blue Helmets: Part 6: UN operation in Cyprus. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Excerpts from S.D. Bailey's How Wars End: The UN and the termination of armed conflict, 1946-1964. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Secretary General's report S, 195514 ()., January 13, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Gyani, Secretary General top secret. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche diary notes., January 1964. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Excerpts from Ruth Bunche's engagement calendar. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Memo: Secretary General to R.J. Bunche re Cyprus brief for Gyani., March 21, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche letter to Gyani re Cyprus brief., March 30, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche note., March 26, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cables: includes list of their contents., April 1964. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Excerpts from Ruth Bunche's engagement calendar. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche Cyprus trip notes., April 8-12, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Notes on meeting w/President Archbishop Makarios., April 9, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., April 11, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., May-June 1964. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cables: includes list of their contents., May-June 1964. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Excerpts from Ruth Bunche's engagement calendar. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cables: includes summary of their contents., July 1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Essay by R.J. Bunche on the UN in., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Draft note to V.P. Kucuk. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., September 5-12, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Cables from R.J. Bunche to Secretary General., August 1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Includes summary of their contents.
  - R.J. Bunche notes., September 1964. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Cables., September-December 1964. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes for Kenya trip., October 1964. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Memo from R.J. Bunche to V.P. Suslov., December 16, 1964.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Cyprus,; Ralph J. Bunche's Middle East Trips., 1965-1969 July 1966-August 1969.; [Box 20, 5 folders]
  - List of R.J. Bunche's press photos., 1966. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cables., 1965. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Includes summary list of their contents.
  - Keesing's., March 13-20 and October 2-9, 1965. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - UN Yearbook., 1966. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche/Role-Bennett., March 1966. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., April 1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Letters/memos/cables., April-December 1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes summary of their contents, mostly re R.J. Bunche's visits to Gaza, Jerusalem, London, Cyprus.
  - UN Emergency Force's magazine The Sand Dune re R.J. Bunche UN Emergency Force visit., July 1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Press clippings includes summary of their contents., July 1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - UN Yearbook., 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's itinerary., January-February, May-June, September-November 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cables/letters/memos., 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Includes summaries of their contents.
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General's office., September 22, 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., September 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Confidential notes of meeting Secretary General/Minister for Foreign Affairs of Cyprus., September 22, 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Secretary General's report on Cyprus to Security Council., November 16, 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General's office., November 18, 22 and 28, 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., December 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - UN Yearbook., 1968. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Cables R.J. Bunche/Rolz-Bennett/Osorio-Taffal/Martola, some confidential. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Memo to R.J. Bunche/Rolz-Bennett from Martola., February 15, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Report to Security Council on Cyprus., June 11, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - UN Yearbook., 1969. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Draft of programs for R.J. Bunche's visit to Nicosia () & revised programme for R.J. Bunche's visit to Cyprus ()., January 8, 1969 August 11, 1969. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Press clippings re R.J. Bunche's visit to Cyprus includes The Blue Beret., August 1969. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Report to Security Council on Cypress., December 2, 1970. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Original press clipping on Cyprus from Daily News., November 17, 1983. (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Dominican Republic; Vietnam; Southern Rhodesia,; Ralph J. Bunche Notes., 1956-1966 1965-1966.; [Boxes 20-21, 6 folders]
  - List of R.J. Bunche press photos., 1967-1968. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes re Dominican Republic. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Secretary General statement re Southern Rhodesia., June 21, 1969. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., March-April 8, 1966. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - U.K. Draft resolution., April 8, 1966. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Chronology., 1964-65. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Background information on Dominican Republic, Southern Rhodesia, and Vietnam. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Memo: Secretary General/R.J. Bunche., June 13, 1963. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Confidential chronology re Secretary General U Thant's efforts to mediate the Vietnam conflict., May 19, 1972. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Letter R.J. Bunche/V.J.Betts., January 8, 1965.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Article 19/R.J. Bunche analysis. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes personal and confidential letter R.J. Bunche/Hobart Taylor ( February 2, 1965.).
  - () chronology., 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - UN Yearbook., 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche Notes., January-October 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Background information on Vietnam. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Notes on meeting w/Adlai Stevenson () & memo to Secretary General from R.J. Bunche ()., February 27, 1965 March 1, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche strictly Confidential note on Vietnam. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - B.E. Urquhart's first draft of R.J. Bunche speech on City of Hope., June 30, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Secretary General's statement re Adlai Stevenson's death., July 14, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General's conference room., July 19, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Conversation between R.J. Bunche & Princess Margaret., November 19, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - chronology., February-March 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - UN Yearbook., 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., 1965. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., April 23-30, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Notes on meeting to discuss Vietnam in Secretary General's conference room., January 10, 17 and 19, February 7 and 28, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January-February 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., March-June 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Confidential copy no.8: Developments in Vietnam., May 1-June 10, 1966; June 21, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Memo: R.J. Bunche/C.A. Stavropoulos., May 4, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., December 17-24, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes re Israel Ambassador Michael Comay's visit to R.J. Bunche in New York hospital., August 18, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles Times article If Thant Quits UN expect R.J. Bunche to follow., June 30, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., July-December 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Arthur Goldberg comes to the hospital & note for file., August 31, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche/U Thant re decision to resign as Secretary General. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General conference room., August 2, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche note on telephone talk with A. Goldberg., September 3, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Notes on visit of L.B. Johnson to U Thant., October 7, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Notes on meeting w/A. Goldberg in Secretary General conference room., November 8, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Vietnam,; Ralph J. Bunche Notes / Schedules,; Ralph J. Bunche, Jr., 1967-1970 1967.; [Boxes 21-22, 8 folders]
  - chronology., 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Background information on Vietnam. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Notes on meeting of Secretary General w/A. Goldberg., January 31, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Letters: L.B. Johnson/Ho Chi Minh. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General conference room., February 17, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Itinerary., January-February 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Press clippings., February-March 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche/U Thant re R.J. Bunche's retirement., January 6 and August 29, 1966. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January-March 1967. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Background Vietnam., March 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Secretary General meetings in conference room., March 14-15, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - U Thant's UN lunch., March 6, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., March 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Confidential Aide memoirs., March 14-15, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Confidential report re Secretary General & Goldberg meeting. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Secretary General & Senate Foreign Relations Committee., March 22, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Confidential Letter: U Thant/Ho Chi Minh., March 24, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Meeting in Secretary General conference room., March 29, 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Itinerary., March 1967. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., April-June 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche itinerary., April-June 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Various newspaper articles re R.J. Bunche & M.L. King Jr.., April 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Note on Visit of Spring Mobilization Representatives., April 17, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Statement of Spring Mobilization Committee., April 15, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Various newspaper articles re R.J. Bunche defends UN., May 1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., July-December 1967. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche itinerary., October-December 1967. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - The Charlotte Observer: article re Vietnam & UN., November 5, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Notes: meeting in Secretary General's office., November 23, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper articles re Thant confirms Viet Cong UN Bid., December 1967. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Background on Vietnam., April 4, June 23 and December 6, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Notes: meetings in Secretary General's office., January 19 and 30, February 1 and 15, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Top Secret memo re Consul-General & Delegate General of Democratic Vietnam., February 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., February 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper articles re Vietnam & R.J. Bunche., February 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Notes on talks w/Secretary General & President Johnson., February 21, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Phone conversation R.J. Bunche & Ambassador Goldberg., February 24, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Secretary General statement., February 24, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., April-June, September 1968. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Notes: meeting in Secretary General's conference Room/office., April 4, June 14, September 23 and 30, 1968. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Background on Vietnam., June 24 and December 18, 1969. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche interviews re Vietnam., 1968/69. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Notes: meetings held in Secretary General office., December 10, 1969 and May 4, 1970. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche - R. Nixon., November 1969. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., June 1968, November 1969, February 1970. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Letter: V.J. Betts - R.J. Bunche ()., September 1970.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Background information:., April 8, 1970, January 22, 1971, May 20, 1971, January 25, 1972. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Middle East 1,; UN Emergency Force Withdrawal., January-May 1967.; [Boxes 22-23, 4 folders]
  - List photos., 1965, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The June War: Some Mysteries Explored by R.B. Parker., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The June War: Origins and Mysteries by R.B. Parker., April 24, 1990. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Mohamed Heikal's Al-Infijar., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Chronology., 1963-1966. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., November 1966. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Background information., June 24 and December 13, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Secretary General's Annual Report., June 16, 1966-June 15, 1967. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - UN Yearbook., 1967. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January 4, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., May 27-June 3, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche itinerary., January-May 1967. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - UN Emergency Force background. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., June 3-10 and July 22-29, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Confidential verbatim record informal meeting government representatives providing contingents for UN Emergency Force., May 17, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Meetings Secretary General w/Ambassador Gideon Rafael & Ambassador Goldberg., May 18, 20, 22, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Cables. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Confidential verbatim record UN Emergency Force Advisory Committee meeting., May 18, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Transcript of background brief by R.J. Bunche to correspondents., May 20, 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Note re take-over/disposal UN Emergency Force installations., May 22, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Middle East 2,; Six-Day War., June-December 1967.; [Box 23, 5 folders]
  - Public statements by Israeli Leaders., May 1967. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Selective chronology of The June War by R.B. Parker. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - List of Middle East reports., May 1967. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Background information re Six-Day War., 1967 and 1992. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Press release: withdrawal of UN Emergency Force., June 3, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letter to New York Times from R.J. Bunche., June 11, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Secretary General's meeting with Eban., June 7, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Basis for functioning of United Nations Truce Supervision Organization., June 13, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letter: H. Brody - R.F. Kennedy., June 15, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes re Baroody Dispute., October 4, 1966. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Security Council's Official Records 1358th meeting (), & 1361st meeting ()., June 13, 1967 June 14, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-Baroody ()., June 14, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - U Thant's farewell lunch for Ambassador Fedorenko., January 19, 1968. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., July 22-29, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Articles re Secretary General's decision to withdraw UN Emergency Force from Egypt., June 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Press release: Secretary General's statement., June 19, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General's statement to General Assembly., June 20, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Meeting: Secretary General with Dean Rusk., June 20, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Personal & confidential letter: R.J. Bunche - E.A. Gross., June 20, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Aide Memoir by D.Hammarskjold., August 5, 1957. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Notes on UN Emergency Force Advisory Committee meetings., November 14, 1956. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General meeting w/Eban., June 22, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., June 1967. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General meeting w/Dr. M. Fawzi () & Eban () & Ambassador Goldberg () & Ambassador El-Kony ()., July 4, 1967 July 4, 1967 July 5, 1967 July 10, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Meetings: Secretary General's conference room () & Secretary General's office ()., July 8 and August 30, 1967 July 10 & July 20, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., July 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Secretary General's Report on UN Emergency Force., July 12, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Meeting: Secretary General with representatives of Iraq & Jordan., July 20, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Meetings in Secretary General's office July 21; July 28; August 14; August 16; August 24, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Secretary General w/Ambassador Rosenne () & w/Ambassador Rafael ()., July 25, 1967 August 10, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes on Expo 67 Trip., August 1967. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Meetings in Secretary General's office () & Secretary General's conference room ()., September 1, 26 and 29, 1967 September 26, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to Secretary General's annual report., September 19, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., June, September 1967. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Personal & confidential letters: R.J. Bunche-F.M. Johnson Jr.., October 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Notes on meeting in Secretary General's office., October 17, 20 & 30, November 23, 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's., November 4-11, 1967. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Secretary General's statement., October 25, 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche handwritten notes., December 1967. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Middle East 3., 1968-1971.; [Boxes 23-24, 8 folders]
  - Appendices., 1968-1971. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    no.1 - Proposals for Action in the Middle East 1969-1971.
    no.2 - Jarring's Reports 1968-1971.
    no.4-7 - Selected confidential papers on the Middle East 1968-1971.
  - Chronology., April 4, June 23, December 6, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., November 16-23, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-Rostow ()., February 7, 14 and 21, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche handwritten notes., January 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Secretary General on Middle East., February 6, 1968.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Pioneer party guest list., June 12, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche note for file., July 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Notes on meetings in Secretary General's office., August 13-15 & 18, 19, 21, 26 & 30, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Notes on meetings in Secretary General's office., September 3 and 9, October 5 and November 9, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Secretary General's 23rd annual report., September 24, 1968. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's handwritten notes., October-November 1968. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Chronology., June 24, 1969, December 18, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., January 25-February 1, May 3-10 and November 15-22, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Memo: R.J. Bunche - Ambassador Jarring., January 17, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Secretary General's remarks., January 18, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Security Council Resolution 242 & Ambassador Jarring., November 22, 1967. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - OPI Daily Press Briefing., February 12, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Estimates on requirements for UN observation operation in Sinai peninsula., February 19, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Confidential letters: G. Jarring-R.J. Bunche; R.J. Bunche-G.I. Smith., April 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Secret: Four power talks - official communique., May 1969. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Meetings in Secretary General's office., June 14, September 29 and November 4, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Official daily press briefing., July 11, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Letters: Ruth Roth-R.J. Bunche, R. Roth-U Thant., September 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General U Thant's public papers., 1968-1971. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Press comminiqué from Tel Aviv., November 4, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Note on Ambassador Ghorra's visit to R.J. Bunche., November 4, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Meeting in Secretary General's office., December 12, 19 and 22, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Transcript: ABC's Issues and Answers., December 28, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Official daily press briefing., December 29, 1969. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., April 11-18, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Appendix no.6: Selected confidential reports on Middle East., 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Meetings in Secretary General's office., January 23, February 6, 25-27 and March 4-5, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Official daily press briefing., March 10, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche statement-Editor's Roundtable., March 12, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., June 6-13, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Meeting in Secretary General's office., May 27, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-G. Jarring., July 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Official daily press briefing., July 28, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - UN Secretariat briefing by R.J. Bunche., July 29, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., August 8-15, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Meeting in Secretary General's office: (Secret)., August 3, 1970 October 16, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's., December 5-12, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Meeting w/Secretary of State Rogers in UN Headquarters., October 16, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - 9th Editor's Roundtable press release., October 20, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement at Editor's Roundtable., March 12, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - B.E. Urquhart's note to correspondents., November 2, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche - G. Jarring ()., December 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Secretary General Address Secretary General to News Media., December 1970. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Secretary General w/Yosef Tekoah., April 5, 1971. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Meeting w/Secretary of State Rogers in Secretary General's office., May 17, 1971. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Confidential note on Big Four Meeting on Middle East., June 24, 1971. (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Bahrain., 1970.; [Box 25, 2 folders]
  - Keesing's., May 23-30, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Background literature on Bahrain. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Confidential Security Council meeting on Bahrain., May 11, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Reader's Digest article Unforgettable R.J. Bunche. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Letters (personal): R.J. Bunche-V.W. Guicciardi., December 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General; R.J. Bunche-Winspeare., January-April 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Letters (personal): R.J. Bunche-Winspeare includes typescript (carbon)., March 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Annex A: Method of Operation; confidential Annex B; Annex C; Annex D., December 1969. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Secretary General note., April 30, 1970.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Annex E: letter M. Vakil-Secretary General., March 9, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Annex F: letter Secretary General-Caradon., March 20, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Annex G: Caradon., March 20, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Confidential: order of procedure & draft method of operation., December 1969. (Box 25, Folder 2)